patexia.com 2014-10-07

# Privacy Policy | Patexia.com

Patexia Inc., which owns and operates the website [www.patexia.com](http://www.patexia.com/) (“the Site”) is committed to protecting your privacy. Maintaining the trust of our users is key to the success of our business and this Privacy Policy is intended to clearly explain our practices so you can feel confident using our services. This Policy explains privacy practices for Patexia.com and the entire Patexia platform. It explains how your personal information is used, and with whom the information may be shared. If you have any questions regarding this policy, please [contact us](http://www.patexia.com/contact_us.html).

This Privacy Policy is part of the [Terms of Service](http://www.patexia.com/terms_of_service.html) for the Patexia platform. By agreeing to the Terms of Service and using the Patexia platform, you agree to be bound by the terms described in this Privacy Policy. Any disputes that arise over privacy between a user and Patexia are subject to the provisions of this Policy and the Terms of Service for the Patexia platform, which are available in our [Terms of Service](http://www.patexia.com/terms_of_service.html).

**1\. Notice**  
This policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you, how we may use or disclose that information and our efforts to protect that information.

_Types of Information Collected_  
In connection with your use of the Site, we ask for and may collect a variety of information from and about you in different ways. For example, when you register an account to become a Patexia user (“User”), we ask for and store your name and/or your business's name, address, email address, password and other identifying contact data. In addition, we may collect information about your background, intellectual properties and legal, technology or other business services that you may provide. We may also collect other information you disclose in any of our online forums, blogs, etc., in the form of comments, questions or answers.

_Use of Cookies and Web Beacons_  
To ensure that the Site is well managed and to facilitate improved navigation within the site, Patexia may use non-identifying “cookies” (a small amount of data sent to a user's web browser from a web server and stored in a user's browser) or “web beacons” (electronic images that allow the website to count visitors who have accessed a particular page and to access certain cookies) to collect aggregate data. Patexia's cookies and web beacons do not generate any personal data, nor do they read any personal data from your computer and are never tied to any personally identifiable information.

_Use of Information_ Patexia uses your personal data to register you as a User of the site and to facilitate transactions for intellectual property or other services between different Users. We will use your e-mail address in order to convey information between Users although your e-mail address and other personal information will only be made visible and available to users at your discretion.

We may aggregate your information, and information about your preferences and activities, with those of all or a particular group of users to obtain some statistics about users’ activities. For example, we may track the number of people who view certain pages, or who use certain features, or we may compile the total dollar amount of sales conducted through our site in a particular geographic region. Such information, and other information we derive from individual Users' information, allows us to continue to grow and provide you with quality service through more accurate marketing and advertising of our services. 

We use information you provide to us to customize your experience on our website. For example, when you login to your account, we will display the members you are connected to and recent posts from your network.

_Unsolicited Messages_  
We will not send unsolicited messages to our Users who have indicated on their Patexia profile that they do not wish to receive such messages.

Patexia will communicate with Users in response to their requests for service or customer support. We will contact you either by phone or by email, according to your preference. We will send you service-related emails if it becomes necessary to do so. For example, if the Patexia Platform will be unavailable for a short time period due to system maintenance, we may notify you via email. Note that we collect information when you interact with Patexia’s member support to gather information to help improve member service and experience.

Patexia may also send you an email in order to notify you of updates to our Privacy Policy, Terms of Service, or other agreements you have with Patexia. 

**2\. Access**  
At any time after you have signed onto the Site, you may edit your Patexia profile to request access to information we have collected regarding you or your business or to notify us of changes to such information. Once confirmed, any new item of information will replace the corresponding information previously provided. You also have the ability to terminate your account by [contacting Patexia](http://www.patexia.com/contact_us.html). Your personal profile and information will be deleted from our database. However, your previous postings and transactions will still be available to users who can view your posts or to entities who were part of that transaction.

**3\. Disclosure of personal information to third parties**  
Patexia takes the privacy of its Users very seriously, and we do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties, except as described in this policy. Under certain business or legal conditions, Patexia may have to disclose your personal data to others.

_Information Sharing_  
Content distributed through Patexia’s sharing features and third party integrations may result in displaying some of your information outside of Patexia.  For example, when you post content that is open for public discussion, your content, including your name as the contributor and photo may be displayed in search engine results. If you choose to engage in public activities on the site, such as posting comments, any information you submit can be read, collected, or used by others. Or, if you have bound your Patexia account to your Facebook account, you can easily share content into both in Patexia as well as to Facebook. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information in public activities or submissions.

_Patexia’s Website and Application_  
We receive information when you interact with and use the Patexia website and platform technology. For instance, we will know when you share updates, submit articles, use Patexia’s research tool, etc.

_Affiliated Third Parties_  
Patexia may employ or engage other companies and individuals to perform necessary business functions on behalf of Patexia (e.g., outside contractors or service providers). If it is necessary to perform these functions, these persons may be provided with personal data, but will be prohibited by contract from using this information for any other purpose other than providing the required services.

_Legally Required Disclosure_  
Under certain circumstances, disclosure of your personal data may be required by law. Patexia may disclose your information if, in its own best judgment, it is required to do so in order to comply with a judicial or governmental subpoena, warrant, or other order, or to a government institution that has asserted its lawful authority to obtain the information.

_Change of Ownership_  
In the event that ownership of Patexia changes as a result of a merger, acquisition or transfer to another company, your personal data may be transferred. If such a transfer takes place, you will be notified of any material changes to the Privacy Policy.

**4\. Security**  
We use industry-standard encryption methods to transmit your personal data from your computer to our platform across the Internet, and we restrict access to any transactional portions of our site to computers running web browsers that support Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol.

Patexia exercises reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal data. However, transmissions administered by humans cannot be guaranteed to be absolutely secure. Patexia will not be liable for unauthorized disclosure of personal data that occurs through no fault of Patexia Inc., including but not limited to, errors in transmission and any unauthorized acts by Patexia's employees.

In addition, remember that you, as a User of our platform, play an important role in security as well. Your password to access our site, which you select at registration, should never be shared with anyone and should be frequently changed. After you have finished using our site, you should log out and close your browser, so no unauthorized persons can access our site with your name and account information. Remember that any information you voluntarily disclose online in any news, message boards, or forums may be collected and used by others without your permission.

Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you transmit such information at your own risk.

**5\. Visitors from outside the United States**  
The Site's offices are located in the United States. If you visit the site from another country, please be aware that information you provide to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of the Site may be processed in and transferred to the United States and will be subject to U.S. law. U.S. privacy and data protection laws may not be equivalent to the laws in your country of residence. By using the Site or providing us with your information, you consent to the collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the United States.

**6\. Legal disclaimers**  
Patexia may provide links to other websites from time to time. Patexia is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these sites. In order to safeguard your privacy, please review the privacy policies of any sites you may visit before providing any personal data to them.

This Privacy Policy only applies to your relationship with Patexia. It does not apply to the interactions you have with any other individual or group on our platform. In particular, Patexia is not responsible for any disclosure made by any other users of the Patexia platform. Your privacy is governed solely by any agreements you may have with other users and is beyond the scope of this Privacy Policy. 

**7\. Changes to this privacy policy**  
It may be necessary from time to time for us to modify this policy to reflect changes in the way we collect and use information, or changes in privacy-related laws, regulations, or industry standards.  Accordingly, we reserve the right to change this policy at any time by notifying users of the changes through an announcement on this website or via email. Data will be handled in accordance with the policy in effect at the time the data is used.

Patexia uses your personal data to maintain your account and to provide you with collaborative services that serve as the core of our online platform. We will NEVER use your personal data for any use other than that for which it is submitted, without your prior consent. 

**8\. Conflict**  
The provisions in the Terms and Conditions will apply where any provisions of the Privacy Policy conflict with the provisions of the Terms and Conditions.

**9\. Contacting Patexia**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or believe that its terms have not been complied with, please [contact Patexia Inc](http://www.patexia.com/contact_us.html).

Policy last updated May 24, 2012  
© Copyright 2012 Patexia Inc. All rights reserved.
